# Kadosa Orosz

orosz.kadosa@gmail.com

Creative Developer with experience working on sophisticated crossplatform Javascript Applications using various MVC, MVVM frameworks. Good at scoping out work, identifying possible bottlenecks and weak points, coming up with solutions and communicating these on multiple levels. Very straightforward and honest, but has a laid-back, relaxed attitude. Generally goes with the flow very well.

Specialises in: Backbone, AngularJS, KnockoutJS, node.js, Phonegap, TweenMax.

Has delivered cutting-edge solutions under tight deadlines for multiple clients, such as: adidas, Barclays, Google, Marks & Spencer, Barclaycard, Gap.



Skills

- JavaScript
- HTML 5
- AngularJS

PhoneGap

GruntJS

- CSS3
- Git

- MODx
- Build Tools
- Backbone.js

Experience

### Kadosa Orosz Ltd

03 / 2014 - Present

Freelance Creative Developer

As a hired gun, I jump in to work on and provide solutions for wideranging projects, from small company websites to cutting-edge digital applications. With long experience of working remotely, I'm well aware of the sensitive nature of such projects and I know the nuances and possess the subtle skills required for making everything go smoothly.

VCCP 07 / 2015 - 07 / 2015

Freelance Front End Developer

**Havas Helia** 05 / 2015 - 07 / 2015

Freelance Front End Developer

**Resn** 06 / 2014 - 12 / 2014

Developer

Developed creative front-end applications ranging from retail campaigns to interactive books. Main focus was on engaging user experience, animation and interaction. Technologies used include Backbone, RequireJS, TweenMax, grunt.

Helped upgrade the backbone based dev stack to improve productivity. Working in a small team, I had wide-ranging responsibilities, including application and database design, deployment and implementation.

Main clients were adidas and Google.

StartJG

12 / 2012 - 03 / 2014

Creative Technologist

Building rapid prototypes, experimenting with cutting edge Javascript technologies (AngularJS, Meteor, Node.js, socket.io) including cross platform touch devices, pushing the boundaries of JS front-end development.

StartJG

08 / 2011 - 12 / 2012

Web Developer

Built cross-platform web application using various Javascript frameworks such as KnockoutJS, AngularJS. Maintained the company's website and rebuilt its intranet site. Gained a lot of experience using CMS systems, building custom applications with MODx.

#### **Various Companies**

08 / 2008 - 07 / 2011

Freelancer Front End Developer

Built websites for many small businesses, mostly webshops, teamed with a back-end developer. Main focus was on clean, pixel-perfect design implementations, cross-browser compatibility and great user experience. This has been a remote position.

Education

#### Technische Universität Dresden

2006 - 2011

## **University of Technology**

2006 - 2011

Computer Science

Interests

Nature, meditation, conciousness, reading, renewable resources, alternative living communities.

Languages

• English

Hungarian

• German

